Jeffrey Fonseca — Resume

■ jeff.fonseca777 [at] gmail.com • **J** +1-573-***-**** Github G: moonpiedumplings • Website/ moonpiedumplings.github.io

Summary

Avid user of Linux & and related technologies for 6 years, intimately familiar with them through personal projects, daily usage, and teaching others. Proficient in both operations, and technical writing/documentation.

I have a site where I document all my work, write about tech, and post guides for other to use: moonpiedumplings.github.io

Professional Experience

Internship at Cirrascale Cloud

- Installed PFSense **①** on Proxmox
- Used packer to automate creation of a MAAS image that deploys Proxmox
- Documented K3's kubernetes, voluster, and Kata-containers on Nvidia GPU's for machine learning operations
- Assisted in building physical servers 🚍, including doing tasks like installing storage 🖴, memory 🎹, or Nvidia GPU's

Date: 7/10/2023 - 8/26/2023

Date: Fall 2023 to Ongoing

Date: 2016 - 2022

WUOTT — Behevioral Health Clinic

- General helpdesk and tech support
- Deployed Meshcentral on an Ubuntu **②** VPS using Docker Compose ***** so I could access, manage, and troubleshoot Windows **■** devices remotely

Independent Organizations

Vice Present of Layer 8 (cybersecurity) Club at Cal State Northridge

CSUN competes in a cybersecurity competition, CCDC. Much of the work here is for that.

- Automated firewalls, backups, password shuffling and container management via Ansible on Linux
- Designed a reproducible development environment for Linux &, Windows = , and Mac & using Nix **
- Introduced and taught people Linux Δ , concepts, and related software \clubsuit , \gt __, \emptyset , \clubsuit , \diamondsuit __, \diamondsuit , \diamondsuit
- Did presentations on Quarto, Github Pages, and Ansible
- Completed multiple NICE challenges, involving Linux Δ , terminal \triangleright __, and database \blacksquare management. Wrote 5 Writeups to assist my teammates.
- Led the CCDC team to regionals as the Linux team lead, taking 7th out of 27 teams

Personal/Educational Projects

- Deployed a Minecraft & server using Podman to an Oracle Cloud VPS
- Built CI/CD Pipelines using GitHub Actions and Docker , to deploy to an AWS SEC2 VPS, for a class project
- Dockerized Node.js ** Python **, and Java ** applications
- Wrote technical documentation to assist students and teachers in AP CSP (E.g. duckdns)
- Deployed Kasmweb on a highly performance optimized Ubuntu **②** VPS
- Worked towards packaging Kasmvnc and OpenStack 🏝 via Nix
- Deployed a point to site Wireguard VPN connection between my router and a VPS
- Installed OpenStack on Rocky Stinux Using Kolla-Ansible
- Deployed a Kubernetes cluster using GitOps and fluxed

Current personal projects can be found on my website, where I document my work as go. I make it a point to pick challenges beyond my current ability. I don't always succeed, but I always grow in the process.

Education

The items in this section are in chronological order, from things I did first to things I did most recently.

- Palomar Community College
 - Intro to OS/Hardware Fundamentals (CSNT 110)
- Graduated from Del Norte High School

 - AP Calculus AB
 AP Computer Science Principles (AP CSP)
- Cal State Northridge Computer Science BS expected graduation 05/27
 - ✓ Introduction to Algorithms and Programming (COMP 110/L) &
 - ☑ Data Structures in Java (COMP 182/L) 👙
 - ⊠ Calculus 2 (CALC 150B)
 - □ Computer Architecture (COMP 122)
 - ☐ Discrete Structures (COMP 256)